-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：tnteva
片名  公众之敌
这是经济大萧条时期的第四年，但对于
约翰・迪林杰，阿尔文・卡佩斯和
娃娃脸尼尔森来说这是抢劫银行的黄金年代
到了，从里面出来
All right,
get out of there.
我们走
Let's go.
往前走，找个位子坐下
All the way down
and take a seat.
快点走，别磨磨蹭蹭的，快点！
Let's go. Stop your
dragging. Let's go! Move!
走，快走
Let's go. Let's go.
- 动手！排队，都排好队！
- 都起来！到右边去
Let's go! Line up! Line up!
DIETRICH: Move! Move! Right turn!
- 跟我走
- 把头低下
Stay with me! PIERPONT:
Keep your head down!
排成一排
Line up! Line up!
大家都准备好了？我们走
DIETRICH: Everybody ready?
Come on.
- 排好队！
- 滚开！
Line up!
Get off me!
- 来啊
- 1
Come on.
PIERPONT: One...
- 现在带我们去更衣室
- …2，3
Now march us to the changing
rooms. ...two, three.
- 走，我们走
- 排好队！
Go. Let's go.
Line up!
我认得你
I know you.
你刚被假释出去还没多久吧
You just got paroled out of
here. You didn't last very long.
是什么时候来着？
When was that?
8星期前
Eight weeks ago.
关了9年
Did nine years.
约翰，约翰・迪林杰
John. John Dillinger.
没错
That's right.
我的朋友都喊我约翰
My friends call me John.
但是像你这种狗娘养的杂碎
最好称呼我迪林杰先生
But a son-of-a-bitch screw like you
better address me as Mr. Dillinger.
打开，打开门，不然我一枪崩了你
Open it! Open it or
I'll blow you in half.
靠墙站好
Against the wall.
现在把你们的衣服脱掉
Take your
clothes off, now!
干得好，小子
DIETRICH: You did it, kid.
那当然，沃特
Sure did, Walter.
把那件该死的夹克给我
Give me
the goddamn jacket.
瑞德！
Red!
快脱，快点
脱衣服，把你的衣服脱了
Come on. Hurry up! PIERPONT: Get
undressed. Take your clothes off.
快点
Come on.
你还敢瞪我！操你妈的！
You eyeballing me,
you son of a bitch?
住手！肖斯！
Cut it out,
Shouse!
肖斯！肖斯！
Shouse! Shouse!
封锁监狱！
Lockdown!
把他们赶到院子里去！
Bring them in
from the yard!
他们在那里！
There they are!
沃特！顶住
Walter! Come on.
沃特・迪崔克死了，都是你搞出来的
Walter Dietrich's dead
'cause of you.
那个该死的警卫不听他的话，强尼
The bastard guard wouldn't
do what he was told, Johnny.
霍莫尔？
Homer?
他得付出点代价，强尼
Just let him
have it, Johnny.
皮特？
Pete?
随便你
It's up to you.
农庄有多远？
How far is the farm?
3.2英里
3.2 miles.
我们都好了
We're ready!
好，我们走
Okay. Let's go!
把这些烧了好吗？宝贝儿
Burn these,
okay, honey?
谢谢你把我们弄出来，瑞德
Thanks for
getting us out, Red.
是强尼定的计划
It was Johnny's plan.
是的，但还是谢谢你
Yeah, but thanks.
先生，让我跟你走
Take me with you, mister.
对不起，我做不到，亲爱的
I can't, darling.
I'm sorry.
欢迎回来，皮特
Welcome back, Pete.
我们去芝加哥搞点钱花花
Let's go to Chicago
and make some money.
佛洛伊德，别跑！
Floyd, halt!
梅尔文，当心！
Melvin, look out!
小白脸佛洛伊德，你被捕了
Pretty Boy Floyd,
you are under arrest.
是查尔斯，查尔斯・佛洛伊德
It's Charles.
Charles Floyd.
- 你是谁？
- 梅尔文・普韦斯，调查局
[备注：联邦调查局（FBI）的前身]
Who are you? Melvin Purvis,
Bureau of Investigation.
你的朋友哈里・坎贝尔呢？
Where is your friend,
Harry Campbell?
我快要死了
I believe
you've killed me.
你就等着烂在地狱里吧
So you can go
rot in hell.
史波特，去看看
Sport.
- 瑞德，打电话给奥斯卡
- 好
Red, call Oscar.
Okay.
- 嗨，洋娃娃
- 我们得去换内裤了
Hi, there, doll.
Let's switch out the shorts.
我们要用到伯曼？
We gonna
use Berman?
对，搞辆普利茅斯还有埃塞克斯
[备注：都是克莱斯勒当时推出的车型]
Yeah. Get a Plymouth
and an Essex.
其他妞呢？
Where them other gals?
- 你叫了马蒂没？
- 当然叫了
You get a hold of Marty?
Sure did.
你还好吗，强尼先生
How you doing,
Mr. Johnny?
很不错，史波特
Doing great, Sport.
上面的主弹簧太紧了
卡壳了两次
The main spring's too tight
on this one. Jammed twice.
我割掉了两圈
I cut off
one coil.
朝右边偏了
And it rides up
and to the right.
我会把卡口弄大的
I widen port.
- 嘿，瑞德
- 嗨，哈里
Hey, Red.
Hi, Harry.
哈里，这是皮特
皮特，这是哈里・伯曼
Harry, this is Pete.
Pete, this is Harry Berman.
嗨，皮特.你好
Hi, Pete.
How you doing?
- 你带了什么车来？
- 这几辆都是直排八缸的
So, what do we got? Got a
couple of nice straight eights.
里面都动过，我改了化油器
Bored them out. Rebuilt
the carburetors myself.
这些车绝对快
These are some
really fast cars.
给各位用那就是绝配
Perfect work cars for
a couple of gentlemen.
- 强尼，过得怎么样？
- 不错
Johnny, how are you?
Good.
马蒂
Marty,
我和我的弟兄们安全了么
tell me that me
and my boys are okay.
只要你还呆在东芝加哥
As long as you stay
in East Chicago,
这里随时随刻都是你的庇护所
you're in safe haven,
any time you want.
这是你的那份
Extra cake's in here.
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿，安娜
Hey, Anna.
我现在的店在芝加哥的哈斯特
到时候过来看看姑娘们
I opened up in Chicago on Halsted
now. Come by and see the girls.
你好吗？
PIERPONT: How are you?
- 趴下！
- 现在趴下，快点！趴下！快点！
On the floor! Now! Now! Do it!
Do it! On the floor, now! Now!
我们玩个游戏吧，经理先生
名字叫做转数字
Let's play a game, Mr. President.
It's called Spin the Dial.
你，把手举高！快点！
还有你，坐下！
PIERPONT: You, hands up!
Come on. And, you, sit down!
趴下！
On the floor!
放轻松
Relax, pops.
打开
Open it up.
都拿来，动作快！都闭嘴！
Empty it! Move, move!
Shut up!
钥匙很多
It's one of these.
英雄都要死，胆小鬼才能活着
你自己选
You can be a dead hero
or a live coward.
- 打开
- 全部！
Get it open.
All of it!
你，举手，快点！
PIERPONT: You, hands up.
Come on!
全部搬干净！
Empty it! All of it!
嘿，坐下！
PIERPONT: Hey, sit down!
把钱推过来！
Push it to me!
别动！
And don't move!
我们有伴了！
PIERPONT: We got company!
走开！
Move out of there!
这钱你留着
我们不抢你的钱，只要银行的钱
You can put it away. Not here for
your money. Here for the bank's money.
我说了，让路！
I said,
move it out of there!
凭什么？
What for?
小姐你过来，我们去兜个风
Come here, sister.
Let's take a ride.
趴下！
DETECTIVE: Get down!
都上车，小姐，你也是
Beat it.
You, too, sister.
过来
Come here.
美女，你会记得的
因为我抓你当过人质
There you go, doll.
Something to remember me by.
你知道不，我不干这活的时候
是个星探
You know, when I'm not doing
this, I'm a scout for the movies.
真的？
Really?
手放一起
Join hands.
我们会在这里冻死的！
We'll freeze here!
不，用不了10分钟你们
就能把手弄出来
No. You'll worm your way out
of there in about 10 minutes.
我们要这些干什么？
Why do we
need this?
因为罪犯们现在飞车四处流窜
跨州犯案
Because criminals flee in fast
automobiles across state lines,
当地的执法机构管不到他们
thereby defeating
local jurisdiction
也没有联邦警察来阻止他们
because there is no federal
police force to stop them.
在我看来，你的调查局为了抓他们
By my tally, your
Bureau wants to spend
花掉了太多纳税人的钱
more taxpayers' dollars
catching crooks
比你抓到的强盗们偷走的钱还要多
than what the crooks you
catch stole in the first place.
这实在荒谬，调查局抓住的绑架犯
Well, that's ridiculous.
The Bureau has apprehended
和银行抢劫犯
kidnappers and
bank robbers who have
- 数量超过了…
- 真的？
stolen up to and in excess of... Really?
你抓了几个？
How many have you
apprehended?
我们逮捕了213个被通缉的重案犯
而且把他们送上了法庭
We have arrested and
arraigned 213 wanted felons.
不，我是问你？
胡佛主管，你抓了几个？
No, I mean you, Director
Hoover. How many?
作为管理人员，我负责指挥
Well, as Director,
I administer.
你个人又抓了几个呢？
How many have you
arrested personally?
我谁都没抓过
I have never
arrested anybody.
你从来没有抓到过罪犯？
You've never
arrested anybody.
当然没有，我是个管理者
Well, of course not.
I am an administrator.
没有现场经验的？
With no field experience.
你不觉得自己非常不称职吗
You are shockingly
unqualified, aren't you, sir?
在你的工作生涯里，从来没有到现场
You have never
personally conducted
参与过罪案调查
a criminal investigation
in the field in your life.
我认为你空有虚名
I think you're a front.
你所谓执法者的形象
I think your prowess
as a lawman is a myth
不过是你手下做宣传的桑丹先生
用头条新闻自吹自擂出来的谎言
created from the hoopla of headlines
by Mr. Suydam, your publicist there.
罪案敢死队，罪恶克星
你想把自己塑造成沙皇么？
[备注:G-Men是1935年的一部电影
Goverment man，不携带武器
只拥有警察的部分权限]
Crimebusters, G-men, you're
setting yourself up as a czar?
跟我预想的大不同
That's running wild
in my estimation.
罪案总是出乎意料
A crime is what
runs wild.
如果这个国家需要像你们这样的机构
If this country requires
a Bureau such as yours,
对于你是否适合执掌它，我表示怀疑
I question whether you are
the person fit to run it.
我可不想让由一群贪财政客
私设的公堂来审判我
Well, I will not be judged by a
kangaroo court of venal politicians.
你的增加拨款申请被否决了
Your appropriation
increase is denied.
把下面这些话发给沃特・温切尔
Feed the following
to Walter Winchell.
麦凯拉就是个原始人
他和我有私仇，一直想弄垮我
McKellar is a Neanderthal, and he is
on a personal vendetta to destroy me.
我们不在他的会议室里和他斗
We will not contest him
in his committee room.
我们要在头版头条上搞他
We will fight him
on the front page.
约翰・迪林杰在哪儿？
Where is John Dillinger?
普韦斯探员，恭喜
Agent Purvis,
congratulations.
谢谢，先生
Thank you, sir.
- 我能问为什么恭喜我吗？
- 他们都准备好了
May I ask why?
They're ready for him.
这位是亨利・桑丹
他是我们公关方面的专家
This is Henry Suydam. He is
our expert in press relations.
首先恭喜你
关于小白脸佛洛伊德的事
Congratulations
for Pretty Boy Floyd,
另外，我个人要向您表示感激
for which you have
my personal gratitude.
然后，从现在起
Second, you are,
as of this moment,
你将是负责芝加哥办事处的特别探员
the Special Agent in Charge
of the Chicago field office.
你能胜任吗，普韦斯探员？
Are you up to that
task, Agent Purvis?
毫无疑问，先生
Absolutely, sir.
下午好，先生们
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
今天，我在此代表美利坚合众国
向众多的罪犯首次宣战
Today, I am declaring the United
States of America's first War on Crime.
请允许我向大家介绍我们最好的
执法人员之一，梅尔文・普韦斯探员
And I'd like to introduce one of our
finest G-men, Agent Melvin Purvis.
普韦斯探员将会负责芝加哥的办事处
Agent Purvis will be in charge
of the field office in Chicago,
这里也是席卷全美的犯罪大潮的中心
the center of the crime
wave sweeping America.
他的任务是抓住头号公敌
约翰・迪林杰
His task will be to get Public
Enemy Number One, John Dillinger.
- 长官？
- 普韦斯先生？
Director?
Mr. Purvis?
能不能说几句？
Say a few words,
would you?
普韦斯先生
你怎么搞定小白脸佛洛伊德？
Mr. Purvis, how did you
run down Pretty Boy Floyd?
在苹果园里
Through an apple orchard.
托尔森先生，等他
接受完采访后告诉他
Mr. Tolson, when he's done, you
tell him if he needs anything,
需要什么，就来找你
you'll get it for him.
还有告诉他，他可以喊我J.E
And tell him
he may call me J. E.
大家都说约翰・迪林杰很狡猾
很难对付
Yeah, but people say John Dillinger's
a lot smarter and a lot tougher.
不管怎么样，我们都会抓到他
Well, nevertheless,
we will get him.
你为什么这么肯定？
What makes
you so sure?
有两样东西
我们有，迪林杰却没有
We have two things
Dillinger does not.
是什么？
What are they?
调查局用于打击犯罪的
先进仪器和高科技
The Bureau's modern techniques
of fighting crime scientifically
以及我们的长官J・艾德加・胡佛
and the visionary
leadership
有预见性的领导才能
of our Director,
J. Edgar Hoover.
那妞一直在看着我
The broad over there is looking at me.
她喜欢我
She likes me.
亲爱的，你好啊？
How you doing,
sweetheart?
阿尔文，很高兴见到你
Alvin.
Good to see you.
好啊
How you doing?
霍莫尔，皮特
Homer. Pete.
我，佛莱蒂和医生想绑架一个人
Me, Freddy and Doc are
looking to snatch a fellow.
他叫艾德・布雷默，圣保罗银行的
我们需要帮手
He's a Saint Paul banker, Ed
Bremer. We need a few more hands.
我不喜欢绑架
I don't like kidnapping.
但是，抢银行越来越难了
Well, robbing banks
is getting tougher.
公众不喜欢绑架案
The public don't
like kidnapping.
谁他妈的管这些人喜不喜欢？
Who gives a damn
what the public likes?
我关心，我得混在他们中间
I do.
I hide out among them.
我们必须考虑他们怎么想的
We gotta care
what they think.
我们还盯上了一辆邮车
We also got a mail train
we're looking at, too.
话说，如果有人被抓了
怎么把他搞出来
By the way, if somebody was to get
pinched, who knows their way around?
联合会有个叫皮卡特的律师
路易斯・皮卡特，我们都找他
Syndicate lawyer named Piquett,
Louis Piquett. We all use him.
这邮车又是怎么回事？
What's it all about,
this train?
需要两三个机灵点的人盯着
Needs two or three more real
right guys to stick it up.
这两个月就准备动手
Be ready in
a couple of months.
大概有170万，是联邦储备
About $1,700,000. It's a
Federal Reserve shipment.
正好做完一票后远走高飞
It's the kind of score
you go away on after.
你想去哪里？
Where you gonna go?
不知道，巴西，古巴
我喜欢瓦拉德罗海滩
I don't know. Brazil,
Cuba. I like Varadero Beach.
你呢？
What about you?
没想过
No plans.
是啊，那么你可以想了
Yeah, well,
you ought to.
我们没法一直搞下去
What we're doing
won't last forever.
我们都是今朝有酒今朝醉
We're having too
good a time today.
从来不去想明天的破事
We ain't thinking
about tomorrow.
- 你记得帮我盯着火车的事，啊？
- 好
Keep me in mind on the train,
would you? All right. Thanks.
你知道他们为了把哈姆・布鲁利
弄出来，花了多少钱？
You know how much they made
taking that Hamm Brewery guy?
- 10万块
- 别激动，霍莫尔
$100,000.
Simmer down, Homer.
别想了，伙计，我们去酒吧
Come on, fellas.
Let's go to the bar.
我骗到3个小娘们
我说这地方是我开的
I got three broads
convinced I own the place.
再见
See you.
霍莫尔最近靠谱么？
Is Homer staying
steady enough?
霍莫尔没事
Homer's fine.
沃特・迪崔克让我学到了一件事
One rule I learned
from Walter Dietrich,
永远别和亡命之徒一起干
never work with people
who are desperate.
好吧，我也学到一条
别去碰女人
Yeah, well, I got a rule,
too. Stay away from the women.
没有了女人，和回到号子里
有什么差别
Without women, it's
like back in the stir.
所以他们才发明了婊子啊
That's why they
invented whores.
嘿，嘿，安娜
Hey, hey, Anna.
好啊，大个子
How are you doing,
big boy?
- 这是？
- 维罗尼卡
Who's this?
Veronica.
维罗尼卡，这是瑞德
Veronica, Red.
- 嗨，强尼
- 嘿，安娜
Hi, Johnny.
Hey, Anna.
我不知道你为什么当那家伙是空气
I don't know why you gave
that fellow the go-by,
不过我要说你做的好
but I'm awful glad
you did.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
比莉・弗莱切特
Billie Frechette.
我请你喝杯？
Can I buy you a drink?
好
Okay.
你有名字么？
You got a name?
嗯
Yeah.
- 杰克
- 跳舞么，杰克？
Jack.
You dance, Jack?
我不会
I don't know how.
别装了
Come on.
你怎么可能不懂跳舞
How come you don't
know how to dance?
弗莱切特
Frechette.
法国人？
That French?
嗯，我爸爸是
名字的最后有个“e”
On my father's side.
There's an "e" at the end.
这首是两拍子的
This is a two-step.
《黑鸟》
Blackbird
有人在等我
Where somebody waits for me
糖很甜蜜，他也甜蜜
Sugar's sweet, so is he
爸爸是法国人，那妈妈呢？
Daddy's French.
What's on the other side?
我妈妈是美浓米尼族的印第安人
My mama's
a Menominee Indian, okay?
大部分男人都不喜欢这血统
Most men don't like that.
我不是大部分
I ain't most men.
真的？
Yeah?
我当过赌场的荷官
在斯都本俱乐部保管衣服
And I've been a dice girl, and I
check coats at the Steuben Club.
你做什么呢？
And what do you do?
我是个偷心的贼
I'm catching up.
为了遇见像你这样的人
Meeting somebody
like you,
黑暗又美丽
dark and beautiful,
就像歌里的鸟
like that bird
in that song.
黑鸟，再见
Blackbird, bye-bye
这里没有人能爱你
No one here can love
或是懂你
Or understand me
你冷了？
You cold?
你到底是做什么的？
What is it exactly
you do for a living?
我是约翰・迪林杰，我抢银行
I'm John Dillinger.
I rob banks.
银行就是所有人都去存钱的地方
That's where all these
people here put their money.
你为什么要告诉我呢？
Why did you
tell me that?
你可以编个故事
You could have
made up a story.
我不会对你撒谎
I'm not gonna
lie to you.
对于一个刚认识的女孩来说
说这事太严肃了吧
That's a serious thing to
say to a girl you just met.
我了解你
I know you.
是吗，我了解你
Well, I don't know you.
我哪里也没有去过
I haven't been anyplace.
我以前呆的也不是什么好地方
Well, some of the places
I've been ain't so hot.
我要去个更好的地方
Where I'm going is
a whole lot better.
你要一起去吗？
Want to come along?
哇，你很性急啊！
Boy, you are in a hurry!
如果你看到我看到的东西
你也会性急的
If you were looking at what I'm
looking at, you'd be in a hurry, too.
好吧
Well,
这次，他们都在看我
it's me they're
looking at this time.
你很漂亮
You're beautiful.
他们看着我是因为
They're looking at me
because they're not used to
没见过有姑娘会穿3块钱的衣服
having a girl in
their restaurant
到他们的餐厅来
in a $3 dress.
听着，洋娃娃
Listen, doll.
那是因为他们只关心你是从哪里来的
That's 'cause they're all
about where people come from.
而我们要去哪里，才是唯一重要的
The only thing that's important
is where somebody's going.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
随我想要去哪里
Anywhere I want.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
嘿，强尼！
Hey, Johnny!
到外面去等我
Go wait for me outside.
吉尔
Gil.
我出来以后就一直
在给弗兰克・尼蒂做事
Ever since I got out, I've
been working for Frank Nitti.
这些人手眼通天，全国都有眼线
These guys are connected to
everybody all over the country now.
他看起来像个理发师
He looks like a barber.
我是菲尔・德安德里尔
你有次抢劫的时候
Phil D'Andrea. Every time I
read about one of your bank jobs
还把顾客的钱还给他们
想到这个，我就对你很感兴趣
where you give the customers
back their money, you crack me up.
如果你需要什么，就找吉尔伯特
You need anything,
ask Gilbert.
吉尔伯特知道怎么找我
Gilbert knows
how to find me.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 那女孩跑哪里去了？
- 我不知道，先生
Where'd that girl go?
I don't know, sir.
她找了辆计程车，就走了
She jumped in a cab
and took off.
我是劳维尔・托马斯
This is
Lowell Thomas.
西弗吉尼亚的消息
From West Virginia
comes accusations
卡内基矿业公司控告
by the Carnegie CoaI company
of Red influence
联邦矿工的罢工行为
给其造成了巨大损失
on the United Mine
Workers' strike.
同时，在威斯康辛德的瑞辛
头号公敌约翰・迪林杰
Meanwhile, in Racine, Wisconsin,
after raiding the American Trust Bank,
洗劫了美国信托银行
Public Enemy Number One
John Dillinger
在联邦警察的追捕下扬长而去
roams the wilds pursued
by the hounds of justice.
在日内瓦，国家联盟
And in Geneva,
the League of Nations
投票通过苏联成为成员
voted the USSR
full membership.
根据银行职员芭芭拉・帕兹科的指认
According to the bank
teller, Barbara Patzke,
这是约翰・迪林杰的衣服
this is
John Dillinger's coat.
圣路易斯的施雷格精品店出品
It's made by Shragge
Quality out of St. Louis.
防风，用了32盎司羊毛，外针脚
售价35美金
Price, $35, windproof
32-ounce wool. Top stitching.
谢谢你，包姆探员
Thank you, Agent Baum.
全国各个办事处的人
Agents in our offices
across the country
都在查卖衣服的店
are identifying every store in the
United States that sold this overcoat.
他们会检查当地所有
出售这件外套的店
Then we will cross-reference
every Dillinger associate
寻找所有迪林杰相关的线索
at locales where
that coat was sold.
他肯定是藏在哪儿了
He was in a place.
他得了感冒，所以买了件外套
He got cold.
He bought a coat.
除非他还在四处流窜
Unless he was
traveling through,
不然就一定躲在附近
he was being
harbored nearby.
只要他敢回来，我们就会等着他
If he returns,
we will be there.
这样我们就有机会抓到约翰・迪林杰
It is by such methods that our
Bureau will get John Dillinger.
多丽丝，你现在给我联系
Now, Doris,
would you please contact
芝加哥电话交换所的主管
他们在6线
the Chicago area telephone
exchange supervisors. There are six.
帮卡特・包姆和我约个时间
Request appointments for
Carter Baum and myself.
先生们
Gentlemen,
等下我们会给你们发
汤普森冲锋枪和勃朗宁自动步枪
shortly you will be provided
Thompson submachine guns, BARs
还有一支点351温彻斯特半自动来福
and a.351 Winchester
semi-automatic rifle.
我们要追捕的是棘手的杀人犯
他们很危险
We are pursuing hardened
killers. They will be dangerous.
你们中谁没准备好的，最好回家去
And those of you who aren't
prepared for that should go.
如果你们谁要走，现在就离开
And if you are going
to go, please go now.
27分钟前有段电话
This is a phone call
conversation
是家车行
from a car dealership
from 27 minutes ago.
哈里・伯曼
Harry Berman.
你走的时候把钥匙放在地板下面
When you drop it, leave
the keys on the floorboard.
- 我搞到辆德索托
- 很好
[备注：也是克莱斯勒的车型]
I got a DeSoto.
Okay.
车里面挺糟的
Interior's no good.
我们怎么去找这个伯曼？
How did we get
to Berman?
从迪林杰的外套入手
Off the Dillinger coat.
衣服是在伊利诺伊州的西西洛买的
The coat was bought
in Cicero, lllinois,
离伯曼的店没多远
a few doors down from
Berman's dealership.
我们调查过伯曼
从卡彭时代起，他就给联合会提供车辆
[卡彭：20世纪初期美国纽约黑帮老大]
Now, we know Berman. He's been supplying
cars to the Syndicate since Capone.
迪林杰肯定是趁在伯曼那里换车的时候
When Dillinger
bought that coat,
买了件衣服
he must have been at
Berman's switching cars.
他们下次打电话交易车子的时候
我们就跟上
As soon as they call to drop
the DeSoto, we'll tail it.
找人轮流监视
I want men on this
around the clock.
先生，需要帮您存衣服吗？
May I check
your coat, sir?
好的，谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你逃走了
You ran out on me.
是你把我丢在街边
You left me standing
on the sidewalk.
如果你要当我的女人
If you're
gonna be my girl,
就发誓绝对不会再这么一走了之
you're gonna have to swear to me
that you'll never ever do that again.
- 嘿，我才不是你的女人
- 棕色的外套
Hey, I'm not your girl.
Brown overcoat.
我才不会答应你呢
And I'm not
gonna say that.
- 我等你说
- 我也在等
I'm waiting.
So am I.
“我再也不会从你身边跑掉”照着说
"I'm never gonna run out on
you ever again. " Say the words.
- 不说
- 我的衣服
No.
My coat.
好吧，那我保证
我绝对不会离开你
Well, I ain't ever gonna run
out on you, and that's a promise.
但是我现在要走
所以，女士…
Well, I want to run
out of here, so, lady...
滚吧，老兄，不用小费了
Hit the road, sport.
Keep the tip.
你再也不用帮人递衣服帽子了
You ain't getting other people's
hats and coats no more neither.
你要干吗？
Why'd you do that?
因为现在你跟我了
'Cause you're with me now.
但是我根本不了解你
I don't know
anything about you.
我在印第安纳州的穆尔斯维尔长大
I was raised on a farm
in Mooresville, Indiana.
我3岁的时候妈妈死了
My mama died
when I was three.
我爸不知道怎样养小孩
只知道狠命地揍我
My daddy beat the hell out of me 'cause
he didn't know no better way to raise me.
我喜欢棒球，看电影，高档衣服
靓车，威士忌，还有你
I like baseball, movies, good
clothes, fast cars, whiskey and you.
你还要知道什么？
What else
you need to know?
坐吧
Have a seat.
你住在这里很久了？
You been living here long?
对
Yeah.
昨天开始
Since yesterday.
嘿
Hey.
我给你准备了些东西
I got you something.
我还是小女孩的时候
BILLIE: When I was a girl,
我们住在弗兰德利的福利院里
we went to live on the
reservation in Flandreau
因为我爸爸死了
'cause my daddy died.
在弗兰德利，什么事情都没发生
In Flandreau,
nothing ever happened.
13岁之后我去了密尔沃基
和我的姑姑伊恩丝住
And when I was 13, I went to live
in Milwaukee with my Aunt Ines.
我们有很多的印第安朋友
We had a lot of
Indian friends,
我们一起去教堂，一起演出
and we went around to
churches and put on plays.
不过那里也没什么有趣的事发生
And nothing exciting ever
happened there, either.
所以除了想到芝加哥来
过自己生活外
So I haven't been anywhere or done
anything except come to Chicago
我哪里都没去过
也没有经历过什么大事
and try to make my way.
你把行李都打包了
You're all packed.
宝贝
Well, baby,
我会带上你
I'm gonna
take you with me.
你将会过上全新的精彩生活
And you're gonna start a whole
new exciting kind of life.
你想要什么？
And what do you want?
一切
Everything.
就现在
Right now.
我是普韦斯
Purvis.
20分钟前，伯曼把德索托
停在了施隆公寓前
Berman dropped the DeSoto at
Sherone Apartments 20 minutes ago.
租给一位薇・史考特小姐的
房间里有人进出
Men go in and out of an apartment
rented to a Miss Vi Scott.
他们都提着很重的手提箱
有个人看起来很像迪林杰
They carry heavy suitcases. One
of them looks like Dillinger.
你的人在哪里？
Where are your men?
在卡兰多和威尔森大街
都在车里
In cars on Clarendon
and Wilson Avenue.
拦截的车呢？巷子里没人管？
Blocking vehicles?
The alley?
有人盯着那辆德索托么？
Who has a line of sight
on the DeSoto to you?
他们知道我们在这儿吗？
有什么可疑行动吗？
Are they aware that we are
here? Any rapid movements?
没有
No.
卡特
Carter,
你到那里去，看着那辆车
you keep an eye on
the DeSoto from there.
巴顿，你跟我走
Barton, you're with me.
什么事？
Yes?
史考特小姐
我是特别探员梅尔文・普韦斯
I'm Special Agent Melvin
Purvis, Miss Scott.
你一个人？
Are you here
by yourself?
不是，和我的未婚夫一起
No. I'm here
with my fiancé.
你未婚夫的名字是？
And what is
your fiancé's name?
莱纳德・麦克亨利
Leonard McHenry.
我们可以进去吗？
May we come in?
好的，请进
Well, please.
我很安全，不过都请进来吧
I'm perfectly safe,
but come on in.
怎么了？
Something wrong?
你有证件吗？
You have identification?
有，当然有
Yeah, sure.
亲爱的，能帮我拿驾驶证过来吗？
在我夹克的口袋
Honey, would you get my driver's
license? It's in my jacket pocket.
没问题
Sure.
我认识你
I know you.
你是…
You're...
你是梅尔文・普韦斯，对吧
You're Melvin Purvis.
Right?
没错，我见过你的照片
Yeah. I seen your picture.
莱纳德，你是做什么工作的？
And what do you do
for a living, Leonard?
我卖女人鞋子
I travel
in ladies' shoes.
亲爱的，给他看看
Show him, honey.
很可爱的鞋子，是吧
Cute, huh?
请你们继续享用晚餐吧
麦克亨利先生
Well, you enjoy the rest
of your dinner, Mr. McHenry.
- 谢谢
- 晚安
Thanks.
Good night.
不准任何人进出
我去叫其他人，你留在这里
No one in or out. I'll get
the others. You stay here.
你就在这里看着那扇门
You watch that door
from right there.
把喜来登那边的人叫来
Get the men
from Sheridan.
调查局，你叫什么名字？
Bureau of Investigation.
What's your name?
你要知道我的名字？
You wanna know
my name?
走吧
Come on.
包姆，你盯着巷子
Baum, you keep an eye
on the alley.
巴顿？
Barton?
巴顿
Barton.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
他们朝东边去了！
They're headed east!
谁在拦截车里的？
Who was in
the blocking car?
是我们
That was us.
我们听到有枪声，就赶过来了
We heard gunfire
so we came here.
是谁？迪林杰？
Who was it?
Dillinger?
我们放跑的不是迪林杰
The man we let get away
wasn't John Dillinger.
是娃娃脸尼尔森
That was Baby Face Nelson.
趴到地板上！现在过去！
Get on the floor!
Now! Go!
你们都起来，靠墙站
Y'all get up
against that wall.
都站过去，你们所有人，这是抢劫！
Go on, all of you. PIERPONT:
This is a stick-up! Up!
把手举起来！
Put them up! Up!
趴下，现在，都趴好
Down on the floor,
now! Down!
把钱拿出来！快点！拿出来！
Put them up! Come on.
Put them up!
这是抢劫！
This is a stick-up!
快走，快点！手举高！
Let's go. Come on.
Up!
举高，让我看到！
Where I can
see them, up!
顾客们，请冷静，不要动
Customers, stay calm.
Don't move.
嘿！你！手举起来！
Hey! You! Up!
- 手举起来！
- 快点！拿走！
Hands up!
Move! Empty it!
约翰・迪林杰从银行抢走了7万4千块
John Dillinger held up
a bank for $74,000
而你连尼尔森都没抓住
while you failed
to arrest Nelson.
长官，我会负全部责任的
Sir, I take
full responsibility.
我还想提个要求
And I would like
to make a request.
我希望能够调些有能力的人
That we transfer men with
special qualifications
把芝加哥这里的人手换掉
to augment the staff
here in Chicago.
有些原来在德克萨斯
和俄克拉荷马做事的
There are some former
Texas and Oklahoma lawmen
现在在达拉斯那边
currently with
the Bureau in Dallas.
你应该知道我要组建什么样的队伍
I thought you understood
what I'm building.
一支最好的，年轻的，专业精英队伍
A modern force of professional
young men of the best sort.
恐怕现在手上的人没法搞定这活
I'm afraid our type
cannot get the job done.
什么？我听不见你说什么？
Excuse me,
I cannot hear you.
我们的人搞不定
Our type cannot
get the job done.
我听不清
I cannot hear you.
我们的人办不成这事
Our type cannot
get the job done.
如果没有合适的人手帮忙
Without qualified help,
我就只能向你辞职了
I would have to resign
this appointment.
不然的话，我的人
会被杀地一干二净
Otherwise, I am leading
my men to slaughter.
托尔森先生会打电话通知你的
普韦斯先生
Mr. Tolson will call you,
Agent Purvis.
他有没有说他长什么样？
Did he say what
he looked like?
没有说
Didn't say.
先生们需要帮忙吗？
You gentlemen
need any help?
谢谢你，不用
Thank you, no.
- 擦亮点
- 早上好
WINSTEAD: Shine?
Morning.
- 你好吗？
- 我挺好
How you doing?
I'm doing all right.
文斯特探员？
Agent Winstead?
- 没错
- 很高兴能帮忙
That's right.
It's a pleasure.
欢迎来到芝加哥，我们有很多事要做
为了抓住迪林杰先生
Welcome to Chicago. We have a lot
of work to do here on Mr. Dillinger.
下一次擦吧
好的，先生，谢谢，先生
Another time.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
祝你今天愉快
Have a nice day.
把强尼・帕顿放到其它四道的前面去
Put Johnny Patton down front
on the other four tracks.
外面很热，是吧？
It's hot out, right?
是啊，弗兰克
Yes, Frank.
上次被那群白痴打中以后
我就再也没有热的感觉了
Ever since those pricks
shot me, I can't get warm.
什么事？
What?
芝加哥来了些人
Some people from
Chicago over there.
强尼
Johnny.
我们25号在图克松碰头
你看怎么样？
What do you say we meet you
in Tucson around the 25th?
- 好的
- 那好
Okay.
All right.
今天我在印第安纳报纸上看到的
I heard one today.
Indiana paper,
通缉约翰・迪林杰
要死的，或者是尸体
"Wanted, John Dillinger,
dead or dead. "
这阵子，我们要让中西部的
条子受累了
I think we wore out
the Midwest for a while.
怎么了？
What?
今晚上来殖民地酒店
是我们自己的店，别客气
Come out to the Colonial tonight.
It's our joint. Be my guest.
有迈阿密最好的牛排
The best steaks in Miami.
你不会要给我们拍照吧？
You're not gonna
take our picture, are you?
不拍照
No pictures.
好，我们会到的
All right.
We'll be there.
谢谢你带我一起旅行
Thank you for taking me
on this trip.
你要去别的地方？洋娃娃
我说对了？
You going somewhere,
doll? Am I?
- 没有
- 别朝骗子撒谎
No.
Don't kid a kidder.
那就不要再耍我
Then don't play me
for a fool.
到最后我肯定还会回斯都本俱乐部
帮人存衣服，我们都清楚
We both know I end up back
checking coats at the Steuben Club,
明摆着的
one way or the other.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
你从来不去想将来
You don't think past today
or tomorrow. And eventually,
他们迟早会抓住你，或者杀了你
they will catch you
or kill you
我不希望亲眼看到这一幕
and I don't want to be
there when that happens.
谁给了你预测未来的水晶球么？
Who gave you
a crystal ball?
我不需要
I don't need one.
去问霍莫尔
Ask Homer.
问霍莫尔什么？
Ask Homer what?
还有他那个该死的笑话
“死的，或者是尸体”
And his goddamn joke,
"dead or dead. "
你哪里都不准去，听见了吗？
You ain't going nowhere,
you hear me?
我会在你的怀里老死的
I'm gonna die an old man
in your arms.
我们比他们强太多了
We're too good for them.
他们不够胆，不够聪明
手脚也不够快
They ain't tough enough,
smart enough or fast enough.
我随时都能去抢银行，随便挑个
I hit any bank
I want any time.
他们却要一直守着所有的银行
They got to be at
every bank all the time.
所以我们才是最厉害的
That's why we're
on top of the world.
没有人能挡住我们
Ain't nobody
lay a glove on us.
没有人
No.
我哪里都不去，你也不准去
I ain't going nowhere.
Neither are you.
你觉得怎样？
What do you got
to say about that?
嗨，老兄
Hi, folks.
下午好
弗兰克・萨利文夫妇，有预定
Afternoon. Got a reservation for
a Mr. and Mrs. Frank Sullivan.
如果你们喜欢的话
我们可以提供三明治和啤酒
I can send up some sandwiches
and beer if you like.
再好不过了
That'd be swell.
我有些朋友应该到这里了
Some friends of mine
should be here already,
J.C.戴维斯
还有一位克拉克先生
a J.C. Davies
and a Mr. Clark?
我想他们大概出去买东西了
Out shopping, I believe.
他们回来的时候，我会告诉说你来了
I'll let them know you're
in when they get back.
好，就这么办
Okey-doke.
电梯朝那边走
The elevator's
right down that way.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
看起来你很需要有人陪啊
You look like you
could use some company.
我和我朋友阿尔伯特王子
能进去坐坐吗？
How's about me and my friend Prince
Albert come and pay you a visit?
你们两个，都请进来吧
Get on in here,
both of you.
强尼！强尼！
BILLIE: Johnny! Johnny!
小姐，请穿上衣服
Put some clothes on, miss.
弟兄们，出什么事情了？
What the hell
happened, boys?
宾馆起火了
There was a fire
in the hotel.
消防员发现了我们的枪
他们叫了条子
Firemen found our guns.
They called the cops.
他们带你去哪里？
Where they taking you?
他们要把我们送去俄亥俄州
We're getting
shanghaied to Ohio.
比莉人呢？
Where's Billie?
你的女人坐上巴士回芝加哥了
Your girl's been put on
a bus back to Chicago.
我们不准备关押她
We ain't holding her.
这边
Right this way.
哟
Well,
这不是干掉小白脸佛洛伊德的人么
here's the man who
killed Pretty Boy Floyd.
幸亏他只是帅而已，对吧
可惜他不叫聪明人佛洛伊德
Damn good thing he was pretty,
'cause he sure wasn't Whiz Kid Floyd.
实话告诉我，普韦斯先生
Tell me something,
Mr. Purvis.
那个家伙，死在施隆公寓的那个
That fellow, the one who got
killed at the Sherone Apartments,
报纸说你发现他的时候，人还活着
the newspaper said
you found him alive.
你能感觉到吧
It's the eyes,
ain't it?
他的眼睛一直在背后盯着你
They look at you
right before they go.
然后突然消失无踪
And then they just
drift away into nothing.
在你熬夜的时候一定帮了不少忙吧
That'll keep
you up nights.
你晚上不睡又靠得什么呢
迪林杰先生？
And what keeps you up
nights, Mr. Dillinger?
咖啡
Coffee.
你表现地像个很有自信的人
普韦斯先生
You act like a confident
man, Mr. Purvis.
你有点本事
You got a few qualities.
也许你远程指挥起来是很不错
Probably pretty good
from a distance,
特别是你人多势众
especially when you got
the fellow outnumbered.
但如果是面对面来斗一场
But up close,
toe to toe,
不死不休，就不好说了
when somebody's about to
die right here, right now,
我早就习惯这种场面了
I'm used to that.
你呢？
What about you?
再见，迪林杰先生
Goodbye, Mr. Dillinger.
我们外面见
I'll see you
down the road.
不，你见不到了
No, you will not.
你离开监狱的唯一方式
The only way that you
will leave a jail cell
就是他们带你去处刑
is when we take you out
to execute you.
是么，我们走着瞧吧
Well, we'll see
about that.
你该给自己再找份工作了，梅尔文
You ought to get yourself
another line of work, Melvin.
嘿，我只是开玩笑
Hey, I was just kidding.
我就让你们再多关我几天
I believe I'm gonna let you
boys keep me here a while.
我们很乐意这么做，强尼
但是不要太得意了
We'd like that, Johnny, but
don't get too comfortable.
他们准备遣送你
They're moving you.
去哪里？
Where to?
印第安纳
Indiana.
为什么？
Why?
我和印第安纳可没有什么感情呢
I have absolutely nothing
I want to do in Indiana.
他到了
He's here.
让开，伙计们，退后
Back up, fellas.
Back up.
现在交给我们吧
把镣铐去掉
We'll take custody now.
Take the manacles off.
再见到印第安纳，你高兴吗？
Are you glad
to see Indiana again?
我猜，就像印第安纳
很高兴见到我一样
About as glad as Indiana
is to see me, I suppose.
你是不是把枪偷偷弄进了
印第安纳州立监狱
Did you smuggle the guns into
Indiana State Penitentiary
策划了9月26日的越狱
for the big break
of September 26th?
伙计，你好奇心太重了
Right now, you're
too inquisitive, buddy.
来，搂住迪林杰
Put your arm
around Dillinger.
嘿，上次你待在穆尔斯维尔
是什么时候？
Hey, when was the last time
you were in Mooresville?
10年前吧
Ten years ago.
我是个冲动的小子
还有，大概还很傻
I was a wild boy, and,
well, I was foolish.
我抢了一家杂货店
I held up a grocery store,
我真不该那么干的
因为摩根先生是个好人
which I never should have done
'cause Mr. Morgan was a good man.
就因为偷了50块，他们判了我10年
把我关进了州立监狱
And they sentenced me to 10 years in
the state penitentiary for a $50 theft.
在监狱里的时候我碰到很多好兄弟
When I was in prison,
I met a lot of good fellows.
所以
So sure, yeah,
我帮他们策划了密歇根市的越狱
为什么不呢？
I helped set up the break
at Michigan City. Why not?
我和我的弟兄们，秤不离砣
I stick with my pals
and my pals stick with me.
强尼，你抢一家银行要多久？
Johnny, how long does it
take you to go through a bank?
哦，大概1分40秒吧
Oh, about one minute,
40 seconds.
精确地说
Flat.
我们走
Let's go.
强尼先生，你的律师来了
Mr. Johnny,
your lawyer's here.
阿尔文・卡佩斯向我大力推荐你
You come highly
recommended by Alvin Karpis.
等到传讯的时候
At the arraignment,
他们准备把我转去州立监狱
they're gonna try and
transfer me to the state pen.
你能为我做什么？
What can you do for me?
你脑子里想的是什么？
What's on your mind?
电椅
The electric chair.
法官大人，我国的法律可曾允许
在传讯中出现如此赤裸裸的偏见么？
Your Honor, are we to have an arraignment
in accord with the laws of this nation
或者说，这是州政府
刻意要营造的氛围？
or is the State to be permitted to
incite an atmosphere of prejudice?
这里的空气中弥漫着憎恨
以及令人不堪忍受的恶意
The very air reeks with the
bloody rancor of intolerant malice!
这些叮当作响的镣铐让我想起了
The clanging of shackles
brings to our minds
沙皇时代的地牢
the dungeons of the czars,
而不是自由旗帜飘扬的美国法庭
not the flag-bedecked liberty
of an American courtroom.
我请求法庭批准，立即取下这些镣铐
I request the court to direct that
those shackles be removed forthwith.
这是个非常危险的人物
法官大人
This is a very dangerous
man, Your Honor.
我需要对这个囚犯的安全负责
And I'm responsible for the
safeguarding of this prisoner.
你是律师吗？
你有什么权力去指使法庭？
Are you a lawyer? What right do
you have to address this court?
好了，将囚犯的镣铐取走
All right. Remove the
shackles from the prisoner.
法官大人，我们希望
更改囚犯的关押地点
Your Honor, we would like
to relocate the prisoner.
只有密歇根市的州立监狱
Only Indiana State
Penitentiary in Michigan City
才能够保证迪林杰不会越狱逃走
can guarantee
Dillinger will not escape.
- 霍莉治安官，你认为呢？
- 法官大人，我同意
Sheriff Holley?
I concur, Your Honor.
霍莉治安官，我觉得你那里的
监狱也很不错
Sheriff Holley, I think this is a
very nice jail you have right here.
是哪里让你觉得不妥了？
What makes you think there's
something wrong with it?
我的监狱没有问题
There's nothing
wrong with my jail.
那是印第安纳最坚固最严密的监狱
It's the strongest jail
in Indiana.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
当然了，我不是想让霍莉女士难堪
But of course, I don't want
to embarrass Mrs. Holley.
我理解，她是位女性
她害怕越狱的发生
I appreciate she's a woman
and she's afraid of an escape.
哦，不不，我不是害怕越狱发生
Oh, no. I'm not afraid
of an escape.
我可以接收约翰・迪林杰
或者其他罪犯
I can take care of John
Dillinger or any other prisoner.
很好
Okay.
迪林杰将会待在这里
Dillinger will stay here.
谢谢你，法官大人
PIQUETT: Thank you,
Your Honor.
我们需要4个月的时间准备辩护
The defense will need four
months to prepare itself.
最多给你10天
It should take 10 days.
10天后开庭，可以认定这位律师
是想滥用私刑
To go to trial in 10 days would
be a legal lynching of this lad.
法律严禁滥用私刑
There's a law
against lynching.
法律同样制裁谋杀！
There's a law
against murder!
那你就好好去读读法典吧
Then observe
the law part.
或者干脆让迪林杰站到墙那边去
Or just stand Dillinger
up against a wall
打死他，朝他开枪就是了
and shoot him.
Just shoot him.
那样的话，就不用浪费国家的钱
来耍这场猴戏了
Then there's no need to throw away
the State's money on this mockery.
肃静
Calm down.
我向庭上道歉
I apologize to the court.
我和鲍勃很尊敬彼此
Bob and I respect
each other very much.
鲍勃你当心噢，要不然他就准备
跟你勾肩搭背了
Watch out or he'll be putting
his arm around you, too.
3月12日，一个月之后开庭
Trial starts in one
month on March 12th.
律师先生，干得漂亮
Attaboy, counselor.
开门
Open the gate.
嘿，卡洪！
Hey, Cahoon!
你过来下
Come here a minute.
过来，萨姆
Come on, Sam.
我们找个地方谈谈
You and me's going places.
喊布赖恩特过来
Call Bryant.
布赖恩特？
Bryant?
叫麦克斯
Call Max.
乱来我就干掉你，别以为我不敢
I'll kill you if I have
to. Don't think I won't.
开门！
Open up!
当心我捅死他
I'll plug him right here.
打开枪械库，快点，打开！
Open the gun safe.
Go on. Open it up!
把监狱长关起来
Lock up the warden.
这不是真的吧
That wasn't real, was it?
我们走
Let's go.
把手举起来
Put your hands up!
哪辆车最快？
Which one of these
here cars is the fastest?
那边的福特，装了最新的V8引擎
That would be that Ford right
there. It's got the new V-8.
我们就挑那辆，走吧
We're gonna take
that one. Go on.
那是莉莉安・霍莉治安官的私人用车
That's Sheriff Lillian
Holley's personal car.
正好
Good.
扬布拉德先生，我们没被跟踪吧？
Mr. Youngblood,
are we clear now?
没有
We are.
好吧，接下来
Okay, then.
哦，别这样，老兄
Oh, come on, buddy.
你需要放松一下，不要紧张
You gotta relax a little
bit. Just take it easy.
你还记不记得“最后的围捕”的歌词？
[备注，20世纪30年代的热门西部歌曲
描述捕猎小牛的场景]
Do you know the words
to The Last Round-Up?
小牛，快点跑
Get along,
little dogies
快点跑，快点跑
Get along, get along
小牛，快点跑，快点跑
Get along, little dogies
Get along
小牛，快点跑，快点跑，快点跑
Get along, little dogies
Get along, get along
小牛，快点跑，快点跑
Get along, little dogies
Get along
我要去参加最后的围捕
I'm a-headed for
the last round-up
他是什么表现？很开心？
How did he act?
Was he jolly?
在路上他还唱歌
Yes. He sang
part of the way.
小牛，快点跑，快点跑，快点跑
Get along, little dogies
Get along, get along
今天，在华盛顿，罗斯福总统说
While in Washington today,
President Roosevelt said,
“约翰・迪林杰愚弄了
"John Dillinger
is making a mockery
这个国家的司法体系”
"of the system of justice
in this country. "
纽约巨人队的经理
约翰.J.麦克格劳去世
The passing of John J. McGraw, long-time
manager of the New York Giants...
- 你好
- 嘿，洋娃娃，是我
Hello.
Hey, doll, it's me.
听着，我不能讲太久，你还好么？
Look, I can't talk long.
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我听见电台里说的了，你怎么样？
I heard it on the radio.
How about you?
我很好，很不错
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
别来芝加哥，强尼
Don't come
to Chicago, Johnny.
这话是什么意思？
What's that
supposed to mean?
我发誓要照顾你的，不是吗？
I promised I'd look
after you, didn't I?
嗯
Yes.
很好，这就是我要做的
Well, then that's
what I'm gonna do.
我说到做到，你应该知道？
You know that,
don't you?
嗯
Yes.
听着，我猜他们在监视我
Look, I think
they're watching me.
我会过去把你救出来，然后照顾你
I'm gonna come get you out
of there and take care of you.
宝贝，别来芝加哥
Baby, don't come
to Chicago!
说你知道了
Say you know it.
跟我说
Say it.
我知道你会照顾我的
I know you will
take care of me.
我爱你
I love you.
早晚
Sooner or later,
她会去找他的
she will go to him
或者他回来看她
or he is gonna
come for her.
- 史波特！
- 强尼先生，你最好呆在那里
Say, Sport! Mr. Johnny, you
got to hold it right there.
你不能再来这里了，强尼先生
Can't stay here
no more, Mr. Johnny.
谁说的？
Says who?
史波特只是听命行事，我也是
Sport's only following
orders. So am I.
他们觉得你可能会来这里
They thought
you might come here.
我没懂
I don't get it.
去问你的兄弟吉尔伯特吧
Talk to your
pal Gilbert.
问什么？
About what?
你得去和吉尔伯特・卡廷纳谈
You gotta talk
to Gilbert Catena.
过来，过来，都滚出去！
都闪开，滚！
Come on. Come on, get out
of here! Beat it! Scram!
竟然没人欢迎我回来
The welcome mat
was not out.
他们一直让我来找你
现在，我来找你
I kept hearing your name.
Now, I'm going to ask you once.
我只问一遍
And I just did.
有人看到他进来了吗？
Anybody see him come in?
我想没有
I don't think so.
你不是想知道我们有没带枪吗？
You want to know
if we're armed?
我们带了
We're armed.
冷静
Calm down.
冷静，冷静
Calm down. Calm down.
嘿，都回去做事
Hey, back to work.
怎么说，菲尔？
What's the deal, Phil?
看看周围，你看到什么了？
Look around.
What do you see?
一大堆的电话
A whole bunch
of telephones.
你应该看到钱
You see money.
上个月开始，有人开始
提供私人连线服务
Last month, there were
independent wire services
告诉下注的人
运动员跑马场的第三场比赛谁赢了
letting bookies know who won the
third race at Sportsman's Park,
本来全国上下有300多家干这个的
现在只有我们一家了
300 of them nationwide.
Now there's only one, ours.
10月23号的时候
你在印第安纳的绿堡抢劫了一家银行
On October 23rd, you robbed a
bank in Greencastle, Indiana.
你带走了74802块
You got away
with $74,802.
你觉得大赚了一笔
You thought that
was a big score.
这些电话每天都能赚这么多
These phones
make that every day.
今天，明天，后天
And it keeps getting made,
day after day after day,
源源不断的钱啊，而且会越赚越多
a river of money, and
it gets deeper and wider,
每一周，每一个月
装进我们的口袋里
week in and week out, month in
and month out, flowing right to us.
除非有条子进来
Unless the cops
come through that door.
但是你收买了条子
让他们离这里远点
Which you pay them
not to do.
没错
Right.
除非你在附近出现
Unless you're around.
那样的话，给多少钱他们也会冲进来
Then they gotta come through
that door no matter what.
你明白意思了？
What does that tell you?
我大受欢迎
I'm popular.
就是说你很坏事
It tells us you're
bad for business.
所以联合会现在有新制度了
So the Syndicate's
got a new policy.
卡佩斯，尼尔森，坎贝尔
像你们这样的人
All the guys like you,
Karpis, Nelson, Campbell,
我们不会帮你洗钱了
也不想再有来往
we ain't laundering your
money or bonds no more.
你也别想再躲到我们的妓院里去
You ain't holing up in
our whorehouses anymore.
没装备，没医生，没避难所
毛都没有，你懂了没？
No armorers, no doctors, no safe
havens, no nothing. You get it?
私底下说，我有什么
能帮你渡过难关的吗？
Personally, you need
something to tide you over?
愿你好运
Good luck to you.
汉密尔顿在底特律
有个34岁的姐姐，逮捕她
Hamilton has a 34-year-old
sister in Detroit. Arrest her.
把所有迪林杰认识的人
医生，家人都抓起来
Pick up all known Dillinger
associates, doctors, family,
皮尔蓬特的妈妈在印第安纳波利斯
Pierpont's mother
in Indianapolis,
迪林杰的家人住在穆尔斯维尔
Dillinger's family
in Mooresville.
我们怀疑他们帮助窝藏逃犯
We suspect them
of harboring.
但是汉密尔顿一家
已经很多年没有联系瑞德了
But Hamilton's family has not
had word from Red in years.
你去说服他们联系瑞德
You convince them
to get word.
制造消息，然后放出去
普韦斯探员
Create informants,
Agent Purvis.
对嫌犯进行长时间的
最严格的审讯
The suspects are to be
interrogated vigorously, grilled,
我们决不同情姑息
no obsolete notions
of sentimentality.
我们进入了新的时代
我们在创造历史
We are in the modern age.
We are making history.
采用最直接，最有效的手段
Take direct,
expedient action.
就像他们在意大利说的
“摘下白手套！”
As they say in Italy these days,
"Take off the white gloves!"
我们说得够明白了吧，普韦斯探员？
Do we understand each
other, Agent Purvis?
这都是些好小伙子
你叫什么名字，孩子？
These are fine young men
here. What's your name, son?
哈里斯
Harris.
全国各地的探员们重拳出击
G- men all over the country
have picked up the gauntlet
给不法分子和穷凶极恶的歹徒
以沉重打击
flung down by the outlaws
and the wanton murderers.
而这些年轻的斗士们
And these junior
crime fighters here,
作为犯罪克星中的新人
these Junior G-men, has,
every one of them,
每一个人都曾经阻止过罪案的发生
stopped some crime
from occurring
抢先一步将罪案扼杀在萌芽之中
and forestalled an entry into
the black book of criminal deeds.
今天，我将向他们颁发奖章
Today, I am rewarding them
with these medals.
我的朋友哈里斯将是第一个
获得奖章的，干的好，孩子
My friend Harris here is
the first. Well done, son.
汤米，你做事赚钱的本事没人可以比
You can size up a score like
nobody's business, Tommy.
你是个好样的
You're a good egg.
但是我不喜欢娃娃脸尼尔森
But I don't like
Baby Face Nelson.
你误会尼尔森了，约翰
他站在你那一边
You got Nelson all wrong, John.
He thinks the world of you.
该死的，整个国家都觉得你是个英雄
Hell, the whole country
thinks you're a goddamn hero.
那银行在哪里？
Where's the bank?
苏福尔斯
Sioux Falls.
尼尔森说那里大概有80万
Nelson says there's
$800,000 in there.
他还说，他给我们找了个
不错的藏身地点
Says he's got us a sweet
little place to hole up
可以躲到风头过去
till after the heat
blows over.
那他来这里干什么？
What's he here for?
约翰，我们要友好相处，好吗？
不然成不了事
John, we gotta all be friends, all
right, or this ain't gonna work.
瑞德告诉你了，抢完这次
我们就把皮尔蓬特和马克利踢掉
Red told you, after the bank,
we bust out Pierpont and Makley.
我们需要仔细合计一下
It'll take a lot
of careful planning.
是啊，然后？
Yeah. So?
这就是头号公敌…约翰・迪林杰
...and Public Enemy
Number One, John Dillinger.
他可能就坐在你的身边
They may be sitting
amongst you.
也许就在你那排
They may be in your row.
看看你的右边
Turn to your right.
再看看你的左边
And turn to your left.
如果你看见他们
给调查局或者当地警局打电话
If you see them, call the Bureau of
Investigation or your local police.
等抢完银行
After the bank,
我们再商量要不要踢了他们，好吗？
we'll figure out if we
can bust them out. Okay?
好吧
Okay.
“不和不认识的人干活”
"You don't work with
people you don't know
“走投无路的时候不干活”
"and you don't work
when you're desperate. "
沃特・迪崔克，还记得吗？
Walter Dietrich.
Remember that?
沃特忘记的是
Walter forgot.
当你绝望的时候
就是你别无选择的时候
When you're desperate,
that's when you got no choice.
我干掉了一个！
I got one!
你干什么？举起手！举起手！
What are you doing? Get your
hands up! Get your hands up!
过来，宝贝儿，我们走，快走
Come on, sugar,
let's go. Come on.
我们要搞的钱在哪里？该死
Where's all the damn money
we came here for?
快点
Come on.
- 开门
- 你在看什么？啊？
Open the door. What
are you looking at, huh?
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
汤米
Tommy.
约翰，我们走！
John, let's go!
快走！该死的，进车里去！
Let's go!
Get in the goddamn car!
快走！快走！快走！
Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
你怎么找到这地方的？
How'd you find
this place?
别担心，没有人能找到我们，走吧
Don't worry. Nobody
will find us. Come on.
有多少钱？
How much?
46120块
$46, 120.
没到80万，是吗？
That'd be less than
$800,000. Am I right?
是不是？
Am I right?
每个人8千
It's $8,000 a man.
把我的份留下，都出去
Leave me
my share and get out.
我们得摆脱尼尔森
We gotta cut loose
from Nelson.
你得休息会儿
You gotta
rest up a while.
不
No.
不行，如果我们不明天一早就离开
No. If we don't get out of
here first thing in the morning,
我们就挂定了
we're gonna wind up dead.
只有你才办得到
Only you're
gonna make it.
去他妈的，别说这种丧气话，瑞德
God damn it, don't talk like that, Red.
不，约翰
我有种感觉，我的时代到头了
No, Johnny. I got a
feeling that my time is up.
时代结束，就是真的结束了
And when your time is up,
your time's up.
瑞德
Red,
看这儿
look here.
明天早上，霍莫尔
你和我一起去雷诺
Tomorrow morning, Homer,
you and me will go to Reno,
一切都会好的
and everything
will be fine.
给我打止疼针
Give me a shot.
只要你告诉我他们藏在哪里
我就给你打针
I'll give you the shot if you
tell me where the gang's holed up.
- 我什么都不知道
- 娃娃脸尼尔森在哪里？
I don't know anything.
Where's Baby Face Nelson?
- 我不知道！
- 迪林杰在哪里？
I don't know!
Where's Dillinger?
- 我要知道他们在哪儿？
- 我不知道！
I wanna know where
they are. I don't know!
告诉我！他们在哪儿？
Tell me!
Where are they?
子弹穿过了他的后脑
The bullet entered
the back of his head.
留在了他的右眼里
It's resting
over his right eye.
不要打岔
Do not interfere.
他的脑子里有水肿，他马上就要死了！
Do not interfere. His brain is
swelling! He will be dead soon!
他很痛苦，我得给他打镇静剂
He's suffering and I
need to sedate him!
还不是时候
Not yet.
如果你敢插手，我就逮捕你
If you interfere,
I will arrest you.
我不知道，求求你，给我打止疼针
妈妈啊，求你了
I don't know! Please, give
me a shot! Oh, mother, please!
- 告诉我他在哪儿！
- 我不知道！
Tell me where he is!
I don't know!
好吧
All right.
在哪儿？
Where?
告诉我！
Tell me!
小波西米亚，小波西米亚
Little Bohemia.
威斯康辛镇的曼尼塔沃什
Manitowish, Wisconsin.
操你妈！
Fuck you!
给我打止疼针
Give me a shot.
小波西米亚在威斯康辛镇的
曼尼塔沃什
Little Bohemia is in
Manitowish, Wisconsin.
萨姆，你来开
Sam, you drive up.
马达拉和克雷格，你们从南边包抄
Madala and Clegg, you cut through
the woods. Stay in the trees.
躲在树林里
Come up on it
from the south,
看清楚他们在不在酒吧里
close enough to see if
they're in the barroom there.
莱斯，罗尔
Rice, Rorer,
你们从北边过去，那里是厨房
come up on it from the
north. The kitchen is there.
你看看他们是不是在客厅里
你们也要躲在树林里
You see if they're in what is probably
the dining room. You stay in the trees.
如果他发现了我们
我们就冲进去
And if he sees them in there? We go in.
如果他没发现呢？
And if he doesn't?
我们照样冲进去
We go in anyway.
这里的房子太多了
There's too much
real estate out here.
他要很多条路可以逃出去
Too many ways for him
to get out,
我们人太少了，没法围捕他
too few of us
to block him in.
我们必须把身后的路封住
We need to blockade
the roads behind us.
我们必须等考利的人包围他
We need to wait for Cowley's
group to surround him.
普韦斯先生，你这么安排不行
Mr. Purvis, this is
not the way to do it.
我不能让他们从手底下逃走
我担不起那个风险
I will not risk their
escaping the Bureau again.
你和赫特去东北方向的转角
You and Hurt take the northeast
corner where the road turns.
坎贝尔，你负责掩护前边
包姆跟我一起走
Cover that and the front.
Campbell, Baum, you're with me.
谢谢，但是我们得走了
Thanks,
but we gotta go.
别走了，留下来吧
我们继续开派对
No, come on, stick
around. Let's have a party.
- 我们明天还要干活
- 傻瓜才干活呢
We gotta work tomorrow.
Aw, work's for mugs.
出去吧！
Get out of here!
你们想看我演詹姆斯・卡格尼吗？
[备注：30年代的电影演员]
You wanna see
my James Cagney?
你们想看我演詹姆斯・卡格尼吗？
啊？啊？
You wanna see my James
Cagney act? Huh? Huh?
你看见什么了？你想说什么？
你知道什么？
What do you see? What do
you say? What do you know?
美女你叫什么名字？
这是你老婆么？傻蛋
What's your name, doll?
This your wife, you dumb egg?
走吧
Go ahead.
停车！
Stop that car!
调查局！
Bureau of Investigation!
停车
Stop that car!
开火！
Fire!
- 别开枪
- 趴到地上！
Don't shoot!
Get on the floor!
强尼！
Johnny!
走啊！
Go!
有人跑了！
Someone got out!
是不是迪林杰？
Is it Dillinger?
我想是的！
I think so!
包姆，往旁边开，顺着林子追
Baum, you drive around
the woods. You flank him!
走
Go.
走！
Go!
加油，瑞德，坚持住
我们就要出去了
Come on, Red, come on. Come
on. We're getting out of here.
嘿，把车钥匙给我
Hey, give me the keys
to that car.
你有没有...
Have you...
你们这些混蛋都穿着防弹背心
All you bastards
wear vests,
我应该打上面呢，还是打下面呢
so I'm gonna give it to you high
and I'm gonna give it to you low.
卡特？
Carter?
是谁干的？ 迪林杰？
Who was it? Dillinger?
尼尔森
Nelson.
长官，有人拦在路中间
Sir, there's somebody
on the road.
考利，你看到车开过没有？
PURVIS: Cowley!
Did you see a car?
有辆福特，朝另外一个方向开去
A Ford, yeah,
it's going the other way.
掉头，马达拉进来
车里是尼尔森
Turn it around! Madala,
get in. It's Nelson!
进来，你这个白痴，进来！
Get in, you dumb bastards!
Get in!
进来，快点，我们走，快
Get in. Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
你从哪里搞来这车的？
Where'd
you get the car?
我在路边干掉了一个条子
I killed a Fed
by the road.
开快点，萨姆！
Faster, Sam!
他们就在后面，霍莫尔！
给他们点颜色瞧瞧
They're behind us.
Let them have it, Homer!
稳住，该死的！
Steady the car,
God damn it!
他妈的！
Shit!
霍莫尔！霍莫尔！
Homer! Homer!
来啊！
Come on!
你见过人死吗？
Have you never seen
a man die before?
闭嘴
Hush up.
约翰，让他去吧
You gotta let go, John.
狗屎！
Bullshit.
你也离开比莉吧
And you gotta
let Billie go, too.
我了解你
I know you.
你绝对不会让任何人失望
You've never let
nobody down.
但是这一次
But this time,
你要想开点
you gotta go on.
你必须学会放手
You gotta let go.
到现在为止
Right now,
迪林杰的所有朋友都死了
all of Dillinger's
friends are dead.
他人就在那里
He is out there.
只剩下他一个人
He is alone.
要追捕他，没有比现在更好的机会了
And there will not be a
better chance to run him down.
是啊，但是他可能出现在
任何一个地方
Yeah, but he could
be anywhere.
也许是这样
He could be anywhere.
但他哪里也不会去
因为他要的东西在这里
But he is not anywhere, because
what he wants is right here.
我不信任政府
I don't believe
in the government,
我也不相信政府会投入所有的钱
and I don't believe in the
government spending all its money,
所以我不愿意参与进去
and hence I don't
take any part of it.
你如果拒绝，你…
And you say no, you...
我应该拒绝接受这些钱
这是政府的钱
I ought to refuse to accept the
money. It's government money.
我不相信政府的拨款
I don't believe in
the government spending.
我不会拿的
I'm not gonna take it.
她在做什么？
What's she doing?
还在听广播
Still listening
to the radio.
长官，我们询问了一个线人
约翰・普罗巴斯克
Sir, we have questioned
a source, John Probasco.
我们相信，他们可能…
We have information that leads
us to believe that they're...
不过从某个方面来说
迪林杰确实推动了法制建设
But Dillinger did aid
law enforcement in one way.
他被认为是议院考虑实施
第一个全国性法案
He's cited as the reason Congress is
considering the first national crime bill,
将犯罪集团跨州犯罪认定为
触犯联邦法令的主要原因
making criminal enterprise across
state lines a federal offense.
与此同时，在北达科他的法戈…
Meanwhile, in Fargo,
North Dakota...
我们的业务已经遍布全国了…
We're building
coast-to-coast.
我们只想要不动声响地赚我们的钱
他们却搞了这么一出
We want it nice and quiet,
and they bring this on us?
弗兰克，冷静点
他们只是抢劫银行
Frank, calm down. They rob banks. Right.
先是一个州，再是另一个，这叫跨州
In one state, then another
state, that's called interstate.
我们这也是跨州，你清醒点
We're coast to coast.
Wake up!
现在他们可以用这些法律
来对付我们了
Now they can use
these laws on us.
现在什么时间了？
BILLIE: What time is it?
星期天早上4点，怎么了？
It's 4:00 a. m., Sunday
morning. What's wrong?
我不想睡了
I don't want to sleep.
为什么？
Why?
因为我要珍惜两个人
在一起的每一刻
Because I want
all the time we got.
如果…
What if
我们能够一起离开这里？
we could get out
of here altogether?
去哪里？
Where?
比如古巴？
Like Cuba?
也许更远的地方
Maybe further.
阿尔文有笔生意，是笔大生意
能赚不少
Alvin's got this job. It's
a big job, a lot of dough.
有了钱我们就可以走了
We could go away on it.
我们找架潘・安姆小型飞机
飞去加拉加斯
We grab a Pan Am
Clipper to Caracas,
然后跑到里约热内卢去晒太阳
吃喝玩乐
scoot on over to Rio
for some fun in the sun,
从地图上消失
slide off the map.
我们可以随时随地
We could go dancing
一起跳舞
and have
a lot of laughs
调笑
any time we want.
愿意和我一起去吗？
Want to take
that ride with me?
好的，我愿意跟你一起去
Yeah, I want to take
that ride with you.
哪里的公寓？
BILLIE: Where's
the apartment?
在奥克利和伯托姆街
Oakley and Potomac.
负责吧台的人叫拉利・斯特朗
All right, the bartender's
name is Larry Strong.
他会把钥匙给你
He'll give you the keys.
谁带你来的？你怎么过来的？
Who brought you?
How did you get here?
出租车啊，我打出租来的
A taxi. I took a taxi.
我们走，快点
弟兄们，把她带出去
Let's go. Let's go, guys.
Come on! Get her outside.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
你们在哪里碰面？
你们躲在哪里了？
Where were you meeting?
Where were you hiding out?
回答他，不然他们会把你丢进
库克郡黑乎乎的监狱里去
REINECKE: Answer him or they'll drop
you in a black hole in Cook County.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
我要去厕所
I have to go
to the bathroom.
上帝啊，看看你都干了什么
Christ, look what you did.
你本来要跟他在哪里见面的？
Where were you
supposed to meet him?
我听不见
I can't hear you.
我听不见！
I can't hear you!
我们本来要在我们的公寓里见面的
We were supposed to
meet at our apartment.
在哪儿？
Where?
爱迪生大街
On Addison.
几号？
What number?
1148号
1148.
什么时候见面？
When?
就现在
Right now.
罗伯茨小姐，你能联系上
普韦斯探员吗？
Miss Roberts, can you
reach Agent Purvis?
不行，他正从印第安纳的
穆尔斯维尔赶回来
No. He's on his way back
from Mooresville, Indiana.
他会直接去库克郡监狱
He's going directly
to Cook County Jail.
约翰・迪林杰躲在爱迪生大街1148号
John Dillinger's holed up
at 1148 Addison.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
好吧
Well,
他现在已经跑远了吧？
way the hell away from
here by now, isn't he?
你想要知道他在哪里？
你这个白痴警察
You wanted to know where
he is, you dumb flatfoot.
普韦斯先生，他们不能
这样对待一位女士
Mr. Purvis, those men cannot
treat a woman in this way.
在司推特街的时候
你就从他身边走过
You walked right past him
on State Street.
你紧张的要死，根本顾不上看周围
You were too scared
to look around.
他就坐在那辆黑色别克的驾驶座里
He was at the curb
in that black Buick.
你问我怎么来的？
我告诉你说我打车来的
You asked me how I got there,
I told you I took a taxi,
你居然相信了
and you believed me?
他把我放下，然后在那儿等我
He dropped me off
and was waiting for me.
你就直接从他身边走过
And you walked
right past him.
如果我的强尼知道你打了他的女人
And when my Johnny finds out
how you slapped around his girl,
死胖子，你知道会发生什么事吗？
you know what happens
to you, fat boy?
放开她
Uncuff her.
厕所在下面的大厅
Restroom is
down the hall.
我站不起来
I can't stand up.
罗杰斯小姐
Miss Rogers.
你好
Hello.
我是马蒂・扎克维奇
有人让我打电话给你，尼蒂先生
I'm Marty Zarkovich. I was
told to call you, Mr. Nitti.
我想我可以安排她去跟警方合作
I think I can get her
to play ball.
一定要搞定
Make sure.
是的，尼蒂先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Nitti.
他们怎么说，安娜？
What did they say, Anna?
他们说要把我送回罗马尼亚
They say they send me
back to Romania.
你知道该怎么做吗？
You know what to do.
他们能收回驱逐出境的法令么？
他们可以么？
Can they fix deportation?
Can they do that?
这群家伙无所不能
These guys
can fix anything.
很好
Okay.
我要你保证
I want guarantee.
如果你帮我们逮捕约翰・迪林杰
If you aid us in
apprehending John Dillinger,
我向你保证
I give you my word
我会通过一切方法
I will do everything I can to
influence Bureau of Immigration
要求调查局帮你留在美国
to let you stay
in America.
这条件不够
Not enough.
最多就这样了
Well, that's all there is.
我要你保证
I want guarantee.
你得不到任何保证
Well, you're not
gonna get one.
我觉得这一切都是你干的
I think you did this.
是你让移民局把我抓起来
把我遣返回罗马尼亚
I think you told Immigration to pick
me up and send me back to Romania.
你怎么和他联系？
How do you
socialize with him?
我们一起出去
We go out.
也许明天晚上，也许不是
Maybe tomorrow night.
Maybe not.
可能是这一周，这个月
也可能永远都不出去
Maybe in a week, a month.
Maybe never.
我无法保证移民局会做什么
I will not guarantee
what Immigration will do,
但我可以确定我能做些什么
but I can guarantee
what I will do.
你如果不合作的话
If you do not cooperate,
48小时之内你就会在
离开这个国家的船上
you will be on a boat out
of this country in 48 hours.
不要和我玩游戏了
Do not play games
with me.
我们是指谁？
Who is "we"?
我，他，还有我手下的一个女孩
波莉・汉米尔顿
Me, him, Polly Hamilton,
one of my girls.
我们怎么知道呢？
How will we know?
等我知道的那天通知你
I call you on the day
when I know.
你进去了？你见到她了？
Did you get in there?
Did you see her?
是的
Yes, I did.
她塞了张纸条给我
She palmed me
this note.
她告诉我上面写了什么
PIQUETT: She told me
what it said.
这主意不错
That's good advice.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
和人见面
Meeting people.
星期二，这辆列车会负责运送
洛克弗德附近7家工厂的工资
On Tuesday, it'll carry the payrolls
for seven factories around Rockford.
入口和出口各有两条
There's two ways in,
two ways out.
医生会提前5分钟切断电话线
Doc cuts the telephone lines
five minutes before.
列车到站之后你和我冲进去
Train arrives,
you and I go in strong.
哈里负责看门放风
Harry handles the door
and the safe.
吉米和佛莱蒂开车
Jimmy and Freddy drive.
你算算大概有多少？
What do you figure?
150万到170万
About $1,500,000
to $1,700,000.
每个人30万
$300,000 each.
- 老天爷啊
- 嗯
Holy cow.
Yeah.
我们星期二动手，星期三我就闪人
We pull this Tuesday,
I'm gone Wednesday.
去哪儿？ 古巴？
Yeah. Where? Cuba?
不
No.
我要走的话得找个比古巴更远的地方
No. Where I go, I'm gonna have
to go a lot farther than Cuba.
哦
Yeah.
嗨，吉米
Hi, Jimmy.
好啊
What do you say?
波莉，吉米回来了！
Polly, Jimmy's back!
跟你说啊
I tell you what, doll.
你，我和波莉今晚去看电影怎么样？
How about you, Polly and me
go out to a movie tonight?
休息一下，消消暑
Get in some refrigeration.
你想去哪里看？
Where do you
want to go?
玛宝，或者拜奥影像吧
Maybe the Marbro
or the Biograph.
吉米晚上带我们去看电影
Jimmy's taking us
to the picture show.
嗯~~
Mmm.
我等会去下店里，晚上做炸鸡
I'll go to the store later and
make fried chicken for dinner.
你去哪儿？
Where you going?
坐有轨电车回去
Streetcar.
我要到城里去拿我的侍者证
I gotta go downtown to get
my waitressing license.
你等一等，我带你去，这里太热了
Hang on a minute. I'll take
you. It's too damn hot in here.
真的？
Yeah?
普韦斯先生，是安娜・塞吉
Mr. Purvis. Anna Sage.
下午好，塞吉小姐
Afternoon, Miss Sage.
今天晚上！
It is tonight!
安娜・塞吉会跟他在一起
Anna Sage will be with him
她穿白色的衬衫，桔黄色的短裙
and will wear a white blouse
over an orange skirt.
他可能化了装
PURVIS: That is how
we will know it is him.
有了安娜，我们就知道是他了
He may have changed
his appearance.
我们还不知道他会去玛宝
还是拜奥影像
And we have not learned if he will
go to the Marbro or the Biograph.
- 有两家电影院？
- 没错
Two theaters?
That's right.
放得什么片子
What's playing?
你问什么？
Excuse me?
玛宝放什么片子？
拜奥影像放什么片子？
What's playing at the Marbro?
What's playing at the Biograph?
玛宝放的是秀兰・邓波儿的
小小姐马克
A Shirley Temple movie called
Little Miss Marker is at the Marbro.
拜奥影像的是黑帮片
The Biograph is playing
a gangster picture
男人世界，克拉克・盖博演的
starring Clark Gable,
Manhattan Melodrama.
约翰・迪林杰不会去看秀兰・邓波儿
John Dillinger ain't going
to a Shirley Temple movie.
芝加哥警察局的扎克维奇
和奥尼尔警官
Sergeants Zarkovich and O'Neill, from
the East Chicago Police Department,
还有文斯特探员会去守着拜奥影像
我也一起去
and Agent Winstead will be
at the Biograph, as will I.
维吉尔・皮特森，你去玛宝那边协调
Now, Virgil Peterson, you
will coordinate the Marbro.
他有枪，而且很危险
He will be armed and
extremely dangerous.
就这里？
Is that it?
嗯
Yep.
- 我很快就回来
- 等等
I'll be right back.
Hold on.
我跟你一起进去
I'll go in with you.
好吧
All right.
我大概要10分钟
It might take 10 minutes.
我们外面碰头
I'll meet you outside.
我希望能看到贝比
这个赛季再挥一次棒
I'd like to see Babe take
one more swing this season.
但是他的腿伤挺严重的，他已经开始
进行挥棒练习了，不过量不大
But his leg is pretty sore. He takes a
bit of batting practice, but not very much.
比分多少了？
What's the score?
小熊队领先，3-2，7局上半
Cubs, 3-2,
top of the 7th.
怪不得他今天没有上场
...that's why he's
out of today's game.
这球很高，一个好球
The pitch is high.
Ball one.
扬基队的首席击球员布洛加
Broaca, the batter
leading off for the Yankees,
没有看清球路
did not see
the ball very well.
情况怎么样了？
What's going on?
没有情况
Nothing yet.
他们没有在玛宝出现
They haven't shown up
at the Marbro.
布莱基！
吉姆！
Blackie!
Jim!
你这个老东西！
Well, you old
son of a gun!
我是说，你看起来起色很不错，吉姆
I say, you're
looking swell, Jim.
德普西对上菲尔波
我们一起去看场好戏？
Let's get a load of this
Dempsey-Firpo binge, shall we?
好啊，好啊，但是我们什么时候才能
再碰头呢？上帝啊，有好几个礼拜了！
Yeah, yeah. But when will we get
together again? Gee, it's been weeks!
那么，明天晚上怎么样？星期六呢？
Well, what about
tomorrow night? Saturday?
他出来的时候我会点雪茄
I will light my cigar
when he's coming out.
扎克维奇，奥尼尔
Zarkovich, O'Neill,
you and your men
你带你们的人去街对面右边的帽子店
take the hat store right
across from the theater.
史密斯，苏兰，克雷格
你们带两个人到后面的巷子守着
Smith, Suran, Clegg, take two
agents, you cover the rear alley.
罗尔和莱斯，你们待在车里
雷因克在北边
And Rorer and Rice, you stay in
the car with Reinecke to the north.
卡莱伦斯和我会在电影院门口的南边
Clarence and I are
gonna be in the doorway
大概30英尺的地方
30 feet south of
the theater entrance.
盖里，你去北边的入口
到车里去守着
Gerry, you're in the tan sedan
just to the north of the entrance.
以防他去北面？
In case he walks north?
他不会朝北走的，普韦斯先生
He ain't gonna walk
north, Mr. Purvis.
他会往南走，抄小巷子回去她家
He's gonna head south, cut through
the alley back to her place.
马达拉
Madala.
你好，格兰杰
Hello, Gallagher.
你好，斯诺
Hello, Snow.
比赛中途把我叫到这里来
Must be something
pretty important,
一定是有什么重要的事情吧
getting me in here in
the middle of the game.
你想要做什么？
What do you want?
我想为朋友帮点小忙
I want to do a little
favor for a friend.
你是政府官员，你可以救他的
You're the governor.
You can save his life.
陪审团说了，他有罪
He's guilty.
The jury says so.
再见，布莱基
Goodbye, Blackie.
再见，吉姆
Goodbye, Jim.
我无能为力，布莱基
I can't help it, Blackie.
我不会让你死的
I'm not gonna
let you die.
我会帮你争取减刑的
I've got to commute you.
让我之后的日子里
都被困在这肮脏的陷阱里
You think you're
doing me a favor
你觉得这是帮我么
by keeping me locked up in this
filthy trap for the rest of my life?
不用了，谢谢，典狱长，我们走吧
No, thanks. Come on,
warden, let's go.
再见，布莱基
So long, Blackie.
孩子，没必要哭哭啼啼的
Kid, keep your chin
up and your nose clean.
怎么来就怎么去，一下子的事
这就是你要走的路
Die the way you lived, all of
a sudden, that's the way to go.
不要拖拖拉拉的
Don't drag it out.
那样活着一点意义都没有
Living like that
doesn't mean a thing.
他说了什么？
What did he say?
我听不清楚
I couldn't hear him.
你来处理，我去给华盛顿打电话
You take care of this. I
need to go call Washington.
你好，比莉
How you doing, Billie?
我是文斯特特别探员
I'm Special Agent Winstead.
如果你是过来继续问我
那些该死的问题…
If you've come here to ask
me more damn questions...
“这个人，那个人，在哪里？”
"Where's this one
or that one?"
我不是过来盘问你的
I didn't come here for
you to tell me something.
我是过来告诉你事情的
I came here to
tell you something.
他们说，你们开枪杀了他
They say you're the man who shot him.
没错，我们其中的一个
That's right.
One of them.
那你为什么要过来看我？
So why are you
coming here to see me?
来看看你们的“功绩”？
To see the damage
you've done?
不是
No.
因为是他要我过来的
I came here because
he asked me to.
他死的时候，说了些话
When he went down,
he said something.
我凑近他的嘴边
I put my ear
next to his mouth,
我想他说的大概是
and what I think
he said was this.
他说
He said,
“帮我告诉比莉”
"Tell Billie for me,
“再见，黑鸟”
"'Bye-bye, blackbird. "'
梅尔文・普韦斯一年后退出了
联邦调查局，1960年，他自杀身亡
比莉・弗莱切特在1936年被释放
并在威斯康辛州终老
TLF中文字幕站
http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net